welcome to our saturday round table
where we talk about our projects but you
know what we've been up to
who would like to start
i can start um
so i for reason score it's a
mass agreement tool i'm still trying to
find a good way to kind of beta test it
i think i mentioned last time i wrote
reached out to some video debaters which
may not be the best users for the tool
but at least they're willing to argue
um they ended up not showing up for the
meeting
just two said they could make it you
know how that happens
um i am offering a 100 gift card to
anyone that wants to have a debate on
the
on the system the winner gets the gift
card and they can split it up if they
want
um uh so one guy said
he he thinks he could find someone
debate stuff so we'll see if he gets
back to me and i posted it for some
other people on there so we'll see if
that comes out i asked my brother to
debate me on it today and i had him look
at
like i have a list of bentleydavis.com
beliefs uh
of things i'm willing to debate people
on it's like well i don't really
disagree with any of those so
um i mean someone could definitely take
the devil's advocate position but i i
feel it works better if they actually
believe the side so
you know ways you can help just anyone
who
thinks they have are passionate about
something that they'd like to debate
also i guess theoretically if you have
something a cause you're passionate
about
it'd be interesting to put the reasons
to support that cause or
especially if it's a piece of
information that a lot of people kind of
disagree with you're having people
trouble understanding it'd be it might
be good to map it out in this because
this will make it to where
you know in a one-minute explanation you
can never really
counter everyone's um
like if they saw a blog post that said
that that was untrue or something like
that it's
you can't really counter everyone's in a
couple minutes but if you can give them
a tool that they can explore
uh then and where they can give feedback
then
i think you have a better capability of
of convincing people uh
because um it bypasses some of the
biases
um not all of them and it lessens them
so
anyway so that's that's where i am with
reason score i'm also
participating in a hackathon this
weekend uh
to support um it's a culture hackathon
um it's by a group that supports under
um underestimated uh
founders and groups like that so usually
women people of color
so i'm mentoring that but so far no
one's had any questions so
i haven't been doing much but
that should accelerate over the weekend
so i'll be busy with that
um i guess that's everything
oh and i just got a job
yeah i forgot to say that so i'm working
part-time for a startup
so 20 hours a week in there um
so that's i'm now um
making not quite enough money to survive
but it's extended my runway
so i might still need a little bit
contract work so if anyone needs a
software engineer for
part-time or contract short-term
projects then that would help me kind of
pad out my
income so that i can focus on game b
that's it so sweet game-made dollars
all right i guess i can go next uh so my
project
is uh both tom ferrari and wiki
elections for the two sides of the same
coin
uh they are a project to fight
misinformation in politics
science and news i've been working with
uh another person in this group radek
or matush depending on what it shows up
as
uh we're bentley helping to get the
prototype developed
uh we've been uh the current version
that's live
is fairly basic but uh radik has been
showing us
the updated version of the prototype on
sort of his own personal server
that's come along nicely um hoping to
see that published
maybe this weekend and then we'll
actually start
getting the conference prototype live
where then we're going to start
looking at i still need a better name
for it for now i'm calling it content
dissection
um and so that's going to be the the
next step
which i think the first you know couple
of examples can probably just be some
basic content that
should be fairly easy to find so some of
it might just be legislation
it could be scientific studies but once
that is available
the next part will be to find sort of
different groups to start giving insight
um as this sort of different content
is dissected to be able to identify the
different areas
the different types of content and so on
but
nothing nothing that i can think of
right now
all right i am jubilee and my projects
are solution raising together tech of
course
and um my new meta modern learning magic
acronym strangely is mlm
i that is more of where my concentration
is these days solution raising i just
show up have a topic and it runs itself
because mlm will help us actually create
the solutions that come on the solution
raising as well as all the personal ones
um this week i wrote out a very rough
draft well my kid was at drama school on
monday
posted it in game b and got a few people
interested
in learning more about the mlm um
and had our first meeting on friday
which was just going to be an faq that i
repeat
until i find the first couple of people
who can complement my skill set in order
to get us to phase one and
i think that both the two people showed
up who were sharon and kerry
might be the two people who are perfect
sharon can kind of help us get a to-do
list
and carrie can knock things off of the
to-do list and then we can recruit based
on whatever she can't do that we don't
want to do as well
and uh there's the what's
podcast that uh
upgrading society i did with them a
couple weeks ago
and it's coming out on monday which both
mentions game b and solution raising
i don't remember if i mentioned together
tech i may have given us a one line this
is also what we're up to
so between then and now i've also have
of course my new fire that i started
and so i wrote a blurb for for jared on
who i am and what i'm what i'm up to
which was also
a little challenging and that is
what i've been up to in the last week
i don't have anything in particular that
i need help with except that i
volunteered to be in the hot seat this
week so we can test the product
for the mlm if
there was no one else and we decided we
were each going to take a turn in the
hot seat and
kind of more decide beforehand who was
going to do it so
you can start that or you can have an
open discussion
dealing with the little the things that
you guys mentioned you need help with
or that can be brought into the product
ironically enough
yeah actually i think we're probably
good to start
the product discussion because it's very
similar to this
instead of bringing our projects and um
so a bit of what the product is the
product will be a six week
course four weeks have a topic so the
first week we're talking about health
and we're doing what we what i assigned
for homework there's you're saying what
yours currently looks like what you
would love it to look like and what is
stopping you from getting there
a little bit like a solution raising and
and then we'll crowdsource solutions so
i didn't give us a topic anyway so the
first week will be health the second
week would be relationships then
time what you spend your time doing
whether that's your job or your hobbies
and then the resources you have and then
the fifth week will be a solution
raising on a on a big topic
that they vote on um and then the fifth
the sixth week they'll be wrapping it up
and saying how did this go for you
maybe you didn't get anything out of the
health one but you got something in the
relationship one right
it's it's continually trying this
process so so that being said i have
although i've done many a solution
raising i haven't actually sat with
people
and done this process and
um it's specifically designed to appeal
to more non-game b
people than game b people um but
hopefully it's more it's more broad and
can appeal to everyone
so i have well i have my statement in my
head which is again i said that i'm not
so great at doing homework i was like oh
i've got a couple things
that i could improve on but if you if
did someone like to share first would
you like me to share mine so that
kind of know what it looks like sounds
like real quick what were the suggested
kind of um sections that you do in the
normal process i know we're not held to
that
health relationships time
how you spend your time as well as
resources and so really anything
anything especially in this time period
um it just gives you a little more focus
to be like is your health where you want
it to be
right is your relationships where you
want them to be for me i was looking at
my life and what i could really use help
with is work life balance
but because i don't work and so i'm 24 7
working
and that is a little bit difficult but
really when i look around at my life the
thing that would be most right now
my house is a disaster it's always a
disaster i'm 40. i don't know if i'm
ever going to have a clean house that's
what it feels like that i
now that i'm a spoonie and i don't have
enough energy there's never enough
energy to go around my house is never
clean
what i would love it to look like is
that it is clean and organized at least
once every two weeks
um so it's starting from fresh
and what's stopping me is i'm not
capable of doing that
i'm capable of kind of following my own
um my own
drive and very rare and i do follow that
when it's time to clean my house but it
doesn't
lead to a clean house doesn't lead to
gee i just woke up and i really want to
do the dishes and do the laundry never
never ironically happens so that is what
what i could use help with
um and this is part of what we're doing
playing with the product is does it make
more sense to now crowdfu
source mine or go on to the next one
what um the first iteration is we all
share
and then we see what came up right when
bradley was talking i came up the
solution for my own right here with a
solution for yours so
if you guys would like to share what is
what your life currently looks like in
that area
what you would love it to look like and
what's stopping you from getting them
so i can go next and i i could think of
something for each of those sections but
i'll just take a simple one
and i don't think
i don't anticipate it actually improving
but uh i mean that will find anything
that i haven't already tried but
let's throw it out there and find out so
i am having i've had this issue for
years
right now several nights a week i wake
up at 3 a.m
in the morning
[Music]
and sometimes i can get back to sleep
but then i'm sleeping
you know my total time in bed is like 10
hours so i feel like the day is gone
um just because i spent two or three
hours in the middle of the night trying
to go asleep and sometimes i don't
so um and it
is for while they're sleeping too much
but
um i i do like getting up but it'd be
nice if i
you know just got up to once to use the
restroom at night and was able to go
right back to sleep
um i have tried gaba
and melatonin um i'm about to try
uh a couple other kind of sleep aid
things
exercise supposed to help um
and so i don't know jubilee or whether
you even want to go but what it is like
it's maybe it's also good to kind of say
what you tried so the next
20 minutes is some people saying have
you tried this it's like yes have you
tried
um yeah so i know exercise should work
and it's on my list to get to doing so
the one of the solutions could be and
help me do that uh
much like your um cleaning the house
thing um
uh yeah yeah so that's that's basically
one of one of my many many issues
all right um i had a problem coming up
with something
like that was
i guess like i feel like
yeah exactly well i get i used to be
conceited now i'm perfect
um i guess
a few things kind of come to mind i'm
not sure how to how to frame them i'll
just pick one randomly
um i
like to believe i have adhd and uh
mine is fairly strong i've had it my
whole life and i can't really take
medication for it because when i took
medication when i was younger it
triggered latent treats
um which wasn't a trade-off that i felt
like making
uh so i was sort of dealt with having
you know fairly strong adhd and having
to do you know do
projects and do work and do that sort of
thing
um i guess so just interested in what's
up there what options are out there or
sort of temporary fixes
actually kind of like a lot of the
aspects of having adhd it's just
the ability to sort of you know
temporarily turn it off because
i want to get something done
all right now we can crowdsource the
solutions and we'll see and it's i also
had a difficulty coming up with
something because i have something in
every area but it was also
that weird i have no idea if anyone can
help with this right there isn't a
solution
at the same time or i already have one
in mind right that i'm either gonna
implement or not implement and so it's
hard to come and kind of trust in the
process and be like hmm
let's see let's see if we can improve
this together um
for adrenal for yours in particular
because i do i have as you said
have abd and my whole life
was jam like relying on adrenaline to
get the information in directly before a
test
and a lot of people i know with adb
who've done that get to the point where
they have burnout
and they can't do that anymore i my
burnout was my brain surgery
and not being able to handle adrenaline
anymore and so there just wasn't that
that forcing it in so i've had to do i
think i mean we know i'm just adding my
way through life and i'm loving that and
it doesn't work in game a right you
can't show up
living in game a and allow that i do
take drugs for abd every once in a while
as you said you can't do that there's a
channel called
how to adhd yep and and she has a lot of
tools and those kind of things
listening to people who who have
adhd right and what has worked for them
that is is beyond drugs and
timers and technology and all of all of
that stuff
is what was coming up for me
while you were trained yeah my brother
has adhd um he was on ritalin for many
years and then worked himself off
um it was sort of effective
and i think he's managed to
build a life around him that kind of
compensates
for it i don't know how solved he feels
i don't think it's solved for him as
well
um i do think
everyone struggles with having to do
attention
a little bit right so i don't think that
i can like focus
for like three hours on something
although sometimes i do get into a flow
state
um and i you know i am coding and i
forget to eat
and forget to sleep um so i don't know
if
if y'all have that in and out as well
but um
it's it is something we all battle with
a little bit and then of course you all
have it at a level that you know i can
compensate for mine
pretty easily uh or when i have trouble
um i could take a break for a little
while and then come back so i
certainly don't have anything like that
i do think i'm a little bit closer on
that side
um from my brother than the average
person
but not nearly the challenge he's had um
yeah so i don't know if i have any
specific things except
um i have heard a lot of people say that
diet
does help them and that's i don't know
if y'all have tried
different types of diets even from going
all the way vegan to all the way
carnivore
for about a month each and see if one of
one of the other helps because i've
known people that
each different extreme helped
um anyways that's the only thought i
have
the problem but the diet thing that's
interesting i mean the other thing that
definitely helps with my add although
my adidas is meditation helps and it's
less
honest like it definitely helps my
nervous system calm down and so i'm able
to just help with the other
it helps a little bit but it's also i
find with all of my neurodiversity
it's less about how it shows up in the
world and more about how the world
treats me
with it and how i respond to that and so
that's the piece that meditation helps
with like it's like
oh this is how my brain is and so it's
okay that other people aren't okay with
it but i have to be okay with it like
this is the only one i got
so this is the one i have and so not
comparing myself to other people
not comparing and not letting other
people compare me to other people
that one's a little harder because
compare another you know it's forcing
them
but not taking that on not not needing
their opinion to be
to be my opinion no i think um some
people hearing that
especially with data you might say i
can't because i have add but i think
jubilee you've probably
experienced that it's not that you're
ever successful
meditating right it's really the attempt
so if you if you even just start for and
you get a minute in and you're thinking
about something else that's okay
go back to it and then fall out and then
go back to it and just not trying to
just they can't do that
i've tried meditation it does help but
it seems very short-lived
like it's i'm educated for 10 minutes
and i feel better for like five
and then back to normal so it's yes
it's a life it's a pro like it's a if
you do it for six months
you notice that your brain and attention
in life in general improves let's say
five ten percent right so it's not
that it's like oh i get a half an hour
if i meditate it's more just that
overall improvement and i just made up
numbers it could be you do that for two
weeks and you get
thirty percent yeah it's like the couch
to 5k
program where it's like if you're if you
sit on a couch all day you're not gonna
do a 5k
but in a couple weeks of doing just i
mean they literally said like go
walk around your house for some people
that was all they could do and then a
week of doing that
uh suddenly you can go around three
times you can drag around the block and
uh it's definitely a muscle that you
have to exercise
and not maybe not everyone can do it
because with that neurodiversity but
i think it's definitely one of those
things to try and i think for a lot of
these issues it's just trying
things out until something works for you
but it's interesting because you do have
to put enough
you have to give it enough time and give
yourself enough patience
for these things to work because none of
them will feel like they're working
when you first do it yeah and it's hard
like to have adhd where you feel like
you can kind of fully like
like for meditation part of it is i
never really feel like i'm doing it
properly
but i still you know go through it it
feels like it helps kind of a bit
um but the long-term thing is
interesting kind of like the opposite of
pot where you know you smoke and it gets
in your system and it stays in there for
a while it's like that right
you do some meditation regularly it gets
in your system you know
it stores in your fat so you know right
one of the other things i've found
because i find that sitting and
meditating is a little difficult and
then i'll do it for like a week and then
it will fall off and i'm like i'll never
do it again clearly because i missed a
day
um you know that all or nothing
mentality but that what i did find
was i meditate while i walk if i go for
a walk
with or without music but generally
without i
end up in a meditative state and it's
just being with my thoughts without
judging them really is meditation and so
i do that more easily when i'm
walking and moving and so i try to go
for a walk in
the forest or near where i live once a
day because that is my meditation
and doing things that make me happy
likes me on the swings um
and and it helps it has the same space
as meditation it feels like i'm cheating
though but it really is like oh it's
something i enjoy
it's where i get my thumb otherwise
other people
like you have to meditate for an hour to
get near where you're kind of
gone through the [ __ ] talk and gotten to
the like in
the ideas that start generating we're
like where did that come from
whereas almost instantly when i walk out
and start walking they start coming
like oh interesting an hour sitting or
an hour walking
and i ca and i you know that's
interesting i find walking like very
sort of you know
brainstorming like i think the people in
my building probably think i don't know
i'm crazy to some extent because like
i'll walk my dog like i'm always staring
almost straight down because that's kind
of
what i do when i i'm walking in and
thought um
and you do that a lot like that's i
probably walk my dog possibly more than
you know like
i've had people say you want your dog a
lot yeah that's
partially because of that i think giving
your brain
something to do one part of your brain
something to do can help
from that kind of squirrel distraction
thing because you are giving it
something so
something simple and repetitive like
walking or
could be folding clothes although it
takes almost too much
mental but find yeah i think that that's
a great technique
um i've been doing meditative walks a
little bit
i've been playing with meditation but i
haven't done it can like i haven't even
done it for like a whole month
daily or anything like that um but i
also
have listened to a lot of people who do
it and some people that go like for
pasta retreats so like a silent
week you have to be careful doing that
because if you have some
background stuff it can come up so you
need to have someone to
to handle that but it they say it takes
a couple days i mean meditation is
is good and and will work overtime but
if you
if you did want it's interesting just
saying it does take
time even if you can do it all at once
but it will take a day or something like
my wife and i are now doing
uh retreats twice a year and they say
for the first day
your mind is still racing and thinking
about what you do for a living or your
life problems and stuff like that
and so the minimum retreat is like three
days because the first day and a half
you're just going to be releasing all
that stuff if you can
you can't really relax until the second
and then you gotta get ready to go
um so yeah giving yourself time i think
is really important
cool thank you yeah i think i have to
watch how to adhd more
i discovered that maybe like a year or
two ago and i've been supporting them on
patreon
almost the entire time um
yeah i didn't actually use it well a lot
of it was like
they produced a lot of content and the
majority of it wasn't that interesting
to me because it was like you know
people's stories and this and that and i
was like that's cool i don't
i have adhd it's not my lifestyle
like it's just a part of it and i'll
deal with that necessary other than that
i'm going to live my life but good just
kind of
revisiting some of the uh these
strategies some of them seem to help
like i've got these little
fidget toys oh yeah oh my desk that help
a bit because sort of that thing that
you're saying like it engages part of
your brain
it does that it does that sort of like
that background part has something to do
now
um i think the best
description of adhd i've ever heard was
like most people sort of have like
an assistant or a secretary you know to
like
to protect their thoughts right we're
like you're having a thought and
a thought tries to come in and the
assistant is like well wait hold on
do you have an appointment okay no he's
busy but
people with adhd lack that person so
just thoughts can walk right in yeah
um and i was like that's the best
explanation of adhd i've ever heard
you know another tool have y'all heard
of the getting things
done process gtd
i started it and so the philosophy of
that
is and i don't know if it helped with
add but it's similar to that
is that you let the thoughts come and
you jot them down in some place
and you don't even have to like arrange
them at that moment and then like once a
day you can sit down and do that
but it lets the thought just like
meditation a lot of times you're
supposed to let the you're not supposed
to be pushing the thoughts away
you let them come in you acknowledge
them and then you let them go
and for some people writing it down will
help them let it go so i don't know if
that would help
um but yeah not so much fighting but
giving them some place to go so that you
can jump back to your thing
right um and i find that helps me a lot
because oftentimes i'll get
i'll be working on something and then i
definitely do that
like not intentionally it's sort of like
i'll just have an idea i don't
want to lose it you know so like i've
got it down it in muscle memory whereas
windows are
notepad entered um yeah right just to
bring
up notepad and then you know jot down
the idea and then
hopefully go back to the previous thing
that i was working on
almost like coming up with a system for
that light okay this notepad's always
open
and then once a day or once a week go
through and put that into the various
folders and documents and stuff like
that yeah and having or having an app on
your phone that's a one click away it's
got to be easy
and some people just keep a notepad in
their back pocket with a little pencil
um yeah on more paper and then i don't i
never look at them again but i do go in
the notes i would suggest if you feel
overwhelmed by the had adhd looking up
the wall of yuck
is the one of the the better tools if
you have it
the wall of the uk wall of yuck
why you ck okay wall of yuck
interesting goes through the different
ways of
with add that you need to like to get
through the wall of yuck the wall of
yuck is like built with all of your past
failures and so every time you go to sit
down to a task all that comes up
and yeah getting getting through it and
you can kind of like hulk your way
through which is the adrenaline which
doesn't really work long term what
is it like what is it a book is it
it's a no it's it's an episode on
how to adhd oh okay cool
sorry so yeah not a specific episode
oh there's my friend my kid's friend
calling her
um yeah good chance
you switch over to bedley's which is how
to get his mind to shut off at night
or his body or something at 3am yeah and
it's funny i used to have trouble
getting to sleep which is that kind of
thing but the meditation helped with
that it's the 3 a.m
and sometimes it's because i my brain
starts up again and
meditation will help but sometimes i
have nothing to think about and i just
am
not tired it's like my body ran out of
melatonin which i am
in my 40s so that could be what's
happening um
and it's gotten more since i fixed my
diet because
now i have more energy during the day
and i think my body's like oh you have
all this energy you need to get up and
do something now that you had to use the
restroom in the middle of the night
um yeah anyway so that's that's
i used to have the issue going to sleep
but now it's it's um
it's waking up in the middle of the
night and feeling sometimes even tired
at all anyways
um this probably won't align with you
but i was waking up at 3am consistently
um and waking up is not really my
problem i can fall asleep at the drop of
a hat i you know like it's it's besides
when i'm super stressed
sometimes i just sleep too much and then
i wake up in the middle of the night
because i got too much sleep
but i was consistently waking up at 3am
and
there is within the chinese
culture the other thing for everything
right every tooth is an organ every and
every time the day is also an organ
and 3am is is like liver and lungs
and i did a liver cleanse and it helped
but i don't like anything that works for
me i never know it's placebo and i'm
making it work or vice versa
but the liver cleanse itself has proof
when you do it i'm actually on
the third month right now i'm drinking
apple juice for six days um
yeah so it's the one cleanse i will do
because there's like actual proof that
it's working when you do it
and then um yeah three
the other thing is to like i like listen
to my body like if i'm up at 3am there's
a reason i'm up at 3am and do that thing
because then i'll just sleep later right
like i'll
in because if i just lay there obsessing
about the fact i'm not asleep
i'm not getting rest i'm not getting
anything done and then i feel
like it just compounds whereas if i get
up and read or i get up and
reading's great for me because it puts
me to sleep right so it's like that's
all i have to do
but if i that's like i'll do a weird
like youtube video at three in the
morning i'll be like well that's
what my body wanted me to do that
wouldn't be your thing but
finding like why why am i awake why did
you wake me up
like what is with this there's usually
some reason
and that was one of the things when i
found the liver in lungs was like well
if i'm at 3am why not do weird research
but also just yeah listening to my body
and being like all right i'm up then
yeah that reminds me that uh i had heard
some similar advice
and it also keeps it to where you're not
associating your bed with being awake
if you don't do and i'm breaking i break
several rules like i
watched videos on my phone before going
to bed so then you associate
the bedroom for you know mentally yeah
yeah but that's that's good i i probably
should try that again getting up and
doing something for a little bit
or reading i didn't really think of that
uh reading does
make me tired so maybe i should try
reading a book
they definitely 3m and then i usually
fall asleep back at like five and then
like i have that extra what's the only
problem
because it's not early enough and not
late enough it's a bad time for sure
yeah because you're like if it's two
then it's like yeah definitely go back
to sleep but if it's like well three
four is the worst for me because four is
like oh my wife wakes up at five
it's just an hour i can should i go back
to sleep and then wake up at like nine
i don't know but yeah
that there's also because of my
disability is to do with sleep and i
google things i get a lot of the ads
for um there's a lot of apps for
sleeping both to put you to sleep
with stories and songs as which i've not
used so i don't know if they work
but there's also ones that are more
about kind of like a fitbit where
they're like test like scene
are you in it and they kind of help you
get back into it and they're like turn
off blue lights now or wear blue light
glasses
and doing that kind of thing if you like
a app telling you what to do yeah i
haven't tried the ones that tell you
what to do i
have uh i got a
a new activity watch um
so it it says it says i was in bed for 9
hours and 13 minutes
so i need this i need to sit down and do
the analysis
um of course actually i think last night
wasn't bad it was the night before that
and i was so tired yesterday
anyways yeah that's a really good thing
i haven't looked into the ones that give
suggestions
or i haven't looked at the suggestions
on this app so maybe i should pull it up
and see what it says all right that's a
good idea
one of the other things that's coming up
is um what was it
it'll come back if it's meant to if it's
meant to
i had some thoughts on yours jubilee
not not not good ones but throw them out
there anyways
um damn hoes i care well i
you know there are some things that i
don't do and i know that
the finances are not the easiest place
for you so making a suggestion of
getting a house cleaner plus
well two things that housekeepers can't
help with if you can end up before it is
one is you feel like you have to pick up
before they get there
so it's a bit of a forcing function um
although i i i keep thinking can i hire
one that will just do the picking up
like i don't mind the vacuuming it's the
picking up i don't know
um like the opposite they clean up they
prep for you to clean
right that's what i want uh and then the
uh
like i i don't do lawn care it's like no
i i'm hiring someone to do that my wife
keeps saying well maybe i'll do it i'm
like well
once you do it we'll stop hiring it but
i'm not
you got to prove you're you could do it
um but perhaps the other thing is that
uh i know down here we have like mighty
maids or something you can hire them for
just a one-time gig
and so they'll reset your house to clean
right
and then it may be a little bit easier
to keep up with
um it's expensive of course but if it's
a one-time thing
not a regular outreach sometimes you can
give that to yourself as a birthday
present or something
or a friend come over and help you clean
once um
might be away yeah no and that was like
after i shared i was like you know
you can hire part of it is like that
needing to pick up first and like i
don't even know
what my house needs to look like for
that person to come i think you're right
though just like i do
when i invite somebody over i don't
invite anyone over to my house i
wouldn't be willing for them to see it
messy
but i still use them coming over as fuel
to clean it
right and so it's like yes that person
coming to clean my house can be fuel to
clean it and get it organized
and then having them come over i think
usually the minimum is four hours or two
hours
and having it like the three of us
because my dad loves me too
living in our bedrooms will they clean
up you know our two bathrooms that are
out there and we
we deal with our rooms and then the the
rest of it can kind of be
done every maybe even once a month have
someone come in
and like like reset it and and do that
and although i don't have the money i
also don't have the money not to
like it's like my home my life functions
better when i have a cleaner or
when my house is clean and yet it's
never going to be clean with me whereas
at least if there's that
reset once a month then i can do it for
a week and then it gets
disaster for a bit like i have it i have
a roomba but i never use it because i
have to clean my floor in order to
use it the uh another thought is there
are people that help with organizing and
so
sometimes they can even suggest
processes to make it easier
to keep things clean as you go
i don't know if that would help or not
but it's just a thought
um yeah
it's that 80d it's like my house gets
messy so easily it's like just bring
this thing here just do that and i have
noticed
if i listen to the reverse it doesn't
get my house clean
but it does help a little bit meaning
that like when i'm walking back to the
kitchen it's like bring that cup with
you in my hand i'm like
later like it's like no not later just a
cup like you're already going there
like cleaning in the same way that i
messed it up like a tiny piece at a time
some things that i've heard that helped
with that is also like putting a little
table by the door
so you can set stuff there that needs to
go now that usually i don't know how big
your house
that would mean i need to have a surface
and any surface
yeah that would be uh the other option
is uh trays
so then you just have a tray and you set
it down and as you do things in there
you're just setting them taking them off
the tray and then you just grab the
whole
i don't know that any of that helps but
it's a thought
that boxes this box goes in my kid's
room this box goes here
my new house is a two-story house so i
may have to put something like that near
the stairwell just because
i'm gonna be especially the first month
or two i'm sure i'm gonna be really
tired of walking up and down stairs
i remember my other point was bentley
although
now this is completely honest of course
brain um what you would mention that now
that you're doing keto
you have more energy i have this weird
block and i've had in my whole life
where like if i don't sleep for eight
hours
i am tired it's literally i need to
think i've slept for eight hours if i'm
wrong on the time if my body doesn't
know
it's like i need to think i've slept for
eight hours and so it's like therefore i
need to no matter how healthy or
unhealthy
i have and it's so it's like it becomes
a cognitive thing more so than a
biological thing but possibly your body
doesn't need as much sleep as it used to
and so just going to sleep later or
doing it like
if that's what keto is doing or just
your rhythm might be changing we used to
wake up in the middle of the night have
some time and then go back to sleep
right that was what we did a hundred
years ago i i think i'm keeping myself
so close to
ketosis that about on 3am in the morning
is my body starts burning fat and has
excess ketones
and so i'm not tired because my body's
like oh i have all this energy it's like
eating a sugar bar
you know or something you have carbs
it's just your body has so much energy
it's like
you got to do something so yeah that's
that's a distinct possibility so maybe i
should
have a little sugar around 1am
then i'll get to hit the sugar crash go
back to sleep i don't know perfect
perfect
also i wasn't going to suggest this to
adriel because i know the answer have
you tried pot
because that is like does not cure adhd
does not help with sleeping too much
but might help with not sleeping enough
yeah that's true like i actually 4 20 is
my time in the morning like if i wake up
past 420 i can't smoke it to go back to
sleep and if i wake up at three in the
morning sometimes i'm like
yup that's the perfect time to yeah it's
a snug some pot
yeah i've tried taking a little
melatonin but some
like you know something at that time
it's backfired and i was like
seriously awake after it i don't know if
my body it just
yeah it's a possibility melatonin your
body was so seriously awake after
yeah yeah it's it's supposed to trigger
your sleep cycle but since it's kind of
a hormone
sometimes your body will just
put the other hormone in it'll detect it
and then overreact with the other
hormone
sergeant melatonin what's happening
doctor valence would be like you
shouldn't sleep yet here are even more
doses
we woke you up for a reason you're not
listening your liver and lungs are
yelling at you
i'm taking your military past and didn't
feel it do anything
hot did it's definitely a bit different
where it's sort of like
after it's done you know after you're
two or three hours it's like okay it's
nap time
especially certain kinds are worse than
others if you hear of uh if you hear a
wheelchair weed that's the stuff you
want that's the stuff after like two
three hours yeah you're done
but that's true might make you hard yeah
yeah i mean i do have beef jerky which
would help but
oh but but you want that one crispy
chippy stuff
i'm sure so yeah and you know it's
mental health-wise i've i wouldn't mind
there's a lot of stuff coming out about
a beneficial use of psychedelics
i would love to get rid of some of my
anxiety not get rid of but
help with my anxiety through that but
that's that can also as well as
that's that's much more dangerous than
what um if it's done wrong but if it's
done right
yeah especially like if you've got
anxiety psychedelics
i think you would want to go through a
certain pack because sometimes they
don't help with anxiety
right right yeah well you need it needs
to be guided by someone who's very
experienced
and understands the science and the and
the history
and mushrooms are pretty safe russia is
just like yeah
fun on your own i was like yeah that's
the difference
yeah ayahuasca just casually do
something
yeah or yeah yeah yeah there's lots
there's a lot of
studies going on right now um and
hopefully in a little while
stay away from salvia oh yeah i haven't
heard of that one
our story together it was my i enjoyed
it i got a lot out of it
i realized the entire universe exists
for the for my amusement and to have fun
and joy and it all figured out the exact
opposite
the whole universe exists for the sole
purpose of betraying him
making his life horrible self is weird
because it
brings you back to the same place when
if you do it again which is great
yeah i guess we're not we're not
solution raising drugs
we're not process raising drugs that
would be actually we did we did totally
solution raise drugs
um but we did kind of come up
not with solution solutions but like i
feel better i feel more
um empowered to like yeah okay now i
know i'm supposed to get a cleaner okay
all right i get it that is not within
like i need to outsource it
and i do have enough savings to be able
to do that um my issue is always like oh
i can't sustain
that long term but
this is honestly about making my life
function so i can create mlm so i can
create solution raising
or whatever else is coming down the
pipeline right like whatever else is
coming out
cleaning my house and focusing on
cleaning it is not helping it's my wall
of yuck and so
getting talking to my roommate slash dad
and finding out
how does this work should we go in on it
together i mean that's kind of what i'd
asked of
got laughed at by my siblings when he
first moved in i'm like i'm gonna be the
one taking on most of this
housework and i can't that we need a
house cleaner cleaner
i pay half and our my siblings pay half
kind of thing because
my dad doesn't like even like i might
move out to the country he's like
i don't know i'm gonna get a roommate i
can't clean i'm like you'll pay a little
more and go get a house cleaner like
that's not
it's this is not this is a lifelong
process for my entire family
no one no one seems to keep a house
cleaned naturally but yeah anyway
that i have solutions so i'm like okay
there's something coming up
i don't know how you guys feel now
compared to the beginning
because now if we have time let's
dissect this part
how was the product for you i i think it
was helpful
um i think like you said one of the
challenges getting into it
is accepting that you know you're
already working on it you already have
some ideas you already put a lot of
thought into it and that
people may be repeating things so i
think having some process
saying um you're not expected to come
without you know or you know
the goal isn't to have it i mean be nice
to have a huge breakthrough but that's
that's not
it's not a waste if that doesn't happen
it's probably a way to say it
um uh and it's just
you're just taking the chance that
someone else may have heard something
that you hadn't discovered
in in what you've worked on so far
um so i think if people if you come in
probably a bad way to say but coming
with really low expectations it'll
probably be good
which is interesting instead of building
it all up uh you're really kind of just
saying hey this is a
this is a just a chance and then i don't
know
whether to make the format to say how
does it look today but also what are
some things i've tried like
i don't know if that's a good idea or
not but i'm just throwing it out there
because it may take too long and also
there might be something about when
people are giving you ideas you don't
have to like give feedback on each one
oh i tried that didn't work oh i tried
that didn't work
and maybe just say oh just just let them
flow out
gather the ones that you want dismiss
the ones you don't but you don't
feel obligated to give feedback um
were some tips that i felt going through
yeah no i think that what you did in the
beginning made sense especially for what
you were doing right it's something
you've been struggling with and here's
everything you tried
um like i could have gone through that
with everything i've tried with cleaning
my house it wouldn't have made as much
sense it's like listen i'm 40 i haven't
figured it out it's not
it's not gonna happen it i do need that
outside outside force right
that is partly why it's like here's
where my health is or whatever it is
here's where my health is and here's
where i need it to be
so hopefully the rest of everyone else
isn't bringing in their bias like oh my
health is
i have six months to live because i have
cancer and someone else is like i have
an essential oil for you and i have it's
like
did you even listen to what their goal
is their goal is to get a year
not to cure it right like not to
you don't get to put your health
obligations on them
it's like what is your goal and where do
you want to get to
do you think it was good the format we
did or we all shared and then we um
and then we kind of just said hey i have
something for that and something for
that
i think it's good in the sense don't
have to as word or as much about someone
hogging all the time
i found it difficult because i'm afraid
listening to the second person's heart
because i have some ideas for the first
person
that are going through my mind so maybe
suggesting that you have a piece of
paper or some way to take notes to think
about it
um because i i sometimes find it hard to
talk to y'all remembering something
um and waiting
but i but that might be better because
then you can also say oh this this i
think would help two of you
you know like we did in this situation
um
i i'd still say try it both ways and and
see if you
because i guess if if someone takes a
really long time and you have three
people you could probably just have that
third person share
the next time as well but and it's it's
four to six people so there's also more
people like we didn't even take the hour
right so it would be more
76 people sharing at the beginning
potentially because the more people
there are the more people who can offer
solutions especially if it is
hey i have a special pill that helps you
sleep right at 3am who would have known
that there is sometimes that person who
does have like sometimes the solution is
something
simple you just need that connection
right like if someone was like yeah i'm
actually looking i
love cleaning houses and i'm really
stressed during the pentagon like i
would love to come over and clean your
house right
is that gonna happen no but like if it
was local people there's a chance that
someone might you know what i mean that
there's
some point of that if there's six of you
there's more likely those things are
gonna come up that was the point
and more people crowd funding and just
yeah that's also the idea so the idea is
i'm creating a six week course
right so we want to have the kind of the
same format for all six weeks so i want
to try it out beforehand to see yes how
does this kind of conversation
work do we all share first
let's try that and then at this in the
sixth one actually i couldn't
but knowing yes to have the peace paper
and pencil right there because you're
absolutely right that is what i should
naturally have done in fact even when
you guys were talking i was like where
is my pen and paper
and and having those kind of
instructions
beforehand of like ideas are going to
come up jot them down let the next
person share
and then popcorn style whatever came up
for you
i think there's also a natural focus
like we we both kind of were like
adriel's is the one we can deal with
um i don't know why maybe because he's
in the middle yeah the 80d somehow
weirdly is an easier thing to deal with
than sleeper cleaning houses
like it was more it's just what came up
and then other you know
ideas come up from there and i think
easiest hardest there's a natural
it may have also been because it was the
last one like it was just uh oh yeah
we've been through all of it
now onto the solutions here was i think
we were just talking about
um that'd be interesting to see if
that's the case yeah
i think that's one of the advantages of
sort of like having in sessions where
you all share and then you all do it
is i feel like if you did it the other
way you would definitely have people a
not necessarily paying as much attention
because like as you get into the thick
of field conversations and ideas
um you're more sort of uh uh uh
or is it there you should be focused on
that but i think it's also it helps
like while you guys were going i was
sort of you know paying attention to the
okay that's sort of the
way that they're sharing and the way
that they're framing it
um i think if you went in stages you
would have like
everyone after the first one would have
sort of had a chance to adjust
i'd be like okay i'm gonna ask this
slightly differently
as opposed to everyone sort of sharing
and being in the same boat
um whether or not that part is better or
not i'm not sure yeah
and i think that is part of it it's
funny i did um life coaching with
with one of the people in game b more
recently and then while i was doing it
they were kind of like making fun of it
and doing it i was like oh yeah this
isn't like
there's a difference between um
using something you're like i'm curious
let's see if this works versus like i
know this isn't gonna work
and it's already like coming to
something like this it's already
hopefully you have a little bit of
curiosity and you're trying to help it
work but also
if you come with too high of
expectations it's not gonna work and if
you come with like i'm gonna break it
right like i have cancer it's all that
for me it's like come on
no that's not no that's not what's
happening but like
so the person involved adjusts where
it's like which obstacle is your big
thing if you have one wish in the world
what would it be and what's stopping you
this is more like what would help you
drastically improve your life right now
right what is one thing that have
changed would help you
and having it broken down into
relationships health and
i guess that's also what i could use
feedback on i have the four for a reason
but they do
those sound like top like is there one
i'm missing or one i could be using
that's different
than self your health relationships
time and resources
no i think that's good i can't think of
anything i think that those are the
important stuff
i mean i guess maybe resources
i was gonna i was wondering whether
there's something about knowledge or
i think health is one of those
they're like foundational things that if
you if you have a problem with those
areas no matter what you're trying to do
it's kind of the hierarchy of needs
right
so as long as health is also understood
in mental health then yeah
yeah and like information is definitely
one of them but they fall it falls into
all of them right like
it's like are you really needing to
learn information for information's sake
right it's like oh i need to learn more
about health or i need to learn more
about business or whatever the
the niche is that would be what you
would bring to it and then yeah have you
tried this book if you read this if you
listen to this podcast right
different very few people have that as a
need i just want to learn more
about what yeah well because i think
most of the solutions kind of end up
being a form of learning
right like we've been saying with 3m all
of a sudden we're talking about sleep
and this and that what can help with
that that's all information
and the same thing with adhd the
meditation that this the going for walks
all that's information so it's like
here's this i mean we're
doing this digitally so that's kind of
the only thing we can provide
is information is even if you know i've
got a bottle
of melatonin on my desk i don't but
theoretically i couldn't give that to
bentley because just here try this yeah
a few times on the part fair enough
yeah no thank you thank you for helping
me play with the product
that was more of a vision in my head i'm
like it'll work so well
and i think it did it worked well and i
think that not having
don't set it up as you're going to solve
all of the world's issues in an hour
solution raising i can still promise
that we literally do but it doesn't get
people there because they're already in
so much disbelief that they're like no
dismissed like have you we really have
come up with a powerful solution for
prisons
and for you know addiction and for all
of these things are they so the solution
no
and it's it's coming to this low
expectations
you will come out feeling better than
you went in hopefully right like
you will have either either more
i don't know an idea that you were on
the right path you're on the wrong path
you're now on the right path or a new
path altogether or
this is not for me this is a horrible
idea why would i let anyone
know about what's wrong with my life and
ask for solutions
and those people this is not before
is there out of those four areas is
there an area
that you cringe at sharing with people
or coming to discuss either for your own
life because you can always pass on that
but also
other people sharing theirs right and
being like i don't want to hear about
other people's either
no i don't think i can't think about
anything but i'm also
very hard to offend or disgust so yeah
like like relationships chances are sex
is going to come up right
because it's part of what's there but
it's not its own category so it's like
those things might come up in the
conversation and someone's like
that's not what i was expecting you know
what i mean that's more about
the differences and like yes different
people are different and that's a big
part of relationships
and with health right like you could end
up with some pretty yes yeah true
yeah gross topics yeah yeah that
these are all equally cringe-worthy
it's true it's true i'm going to be
cringing at people's time they spend and
their resources
you want what no game a stamp that
gaming all over the place it's like
right it's their life they will have to
choose
you're allowed
to drop off a few minutes early i got a
meeting starting in a few minutes
but it was fun and uh all right
on the flip side and next friday we'll
discuss who's in the hot seat next week
or do you guys want to discuss that now
so that we know who is there
one of you can take the hot seat let's
let me let's discuss it friday
cool bye guys all right bye
before we we stop going live now that
billy's not here let's talk about him uh
when he mentioned his brother and he was
like um
we don't we agree on everything i'm like
we don't have that problem in our
sibling group so what we could possibly
do
is you and me could find something we
disagree on and do the debate thing for
him in that hour but i don't know
whether that would work right but we can
offer
just like we focused on my product right
like hey let's
pick something we disagree on and uh
figure that out right which side i
my issue with debating like i used to
love debating including even the
references and stuff
but no i always hated the references but
at least i saw the value in them
now i'm just like it's a gut feeling
like oh my god
you and you can't counteract that right
like it's not it's not a reason thing
it's like i went so much data
like data like the gut feeling thing
i think that's how everyone operates
right like that's actually how decisions
are made
is you make your decision and then you
look for stuff to back it up
like you back up how you all already did
but i think that's how everyone is going
to operate
which means that whatever tool right
whether it's reason score or wiki
election or what
it needs to be able to handle that so it
sort of needs to be able to like provide
that underlying information
it's never going to work for everyone it
kind of has to be able to you know to
chip away at that like
oh this is pretty convincingly
not agreeing with what i believe
interesting right and then you might go
look
like is it biased it doesn't look like
it's biased ah crap
um but so i think it is like just purely
whatever evidence you have chosen to
believe
because of your bias great bring that
yeah and that is part like part of it is
because
it's always valid to be like what are
those references but when you're a jack
of all trades and you don't have a
memory and
you know like it's like i don't actually
know where i learned that and i don't
know if it's true or not because i don't
know if i learned where i learned it
right
and so that's part of why i became
obsessed with
having that like imbd for all
information where it's just as easy to
look up anything
so that we can like nip this in the bud
like it's like
you know it doesn't matter where i got
my reference it matters what the actual
truth is or not because that's where all
of our information comes from right he's
a telephone
leg i don't know what i learned that and
i don't know oh yeah and then still
things that are easily
referenced and i'm like i believe that
for 20 years
is it true like who haven't learned that
there's been a few times where it's like
middle and some until and i'm like i'm
not saying you're wrong
but if you're wrong it shakes my
worldview so i'm just gonna need to take
a moment and google this
like you might be right i was the
population of iceland was one of them i
don't remember
i was like what do you mean there's only
i think it's a hundred thousand or
some very low amount i was like what how
it's like they are a tiny island i don't
know why i thought that there would be
more people
but that's one of the reasons that they
function when they
their economy came back and stuff other
other things that
that rock my world do especially if
there's to do with science and biology
and such and and yet there's tons of
things that we believe that are not
true but like most people believe them
so they're just most people believe them
we took a poll
and so yeah anyway so we could offer
that to him
yeah hey what's the other siblings what
it would look like if something was
totally one-sided
right like if you wanted to use it for a
soapbox to be like here's all the
evidence
as to why i'm right and to start there
which i think we may have talked
and i'm not sure why like or i really
may have suggested that in the past i
don't recall why that wasn't
a solution but i kind of feel like a it
needs to be able to do that it's people
to tell a one-sided story
but then that's also baked because you
know if you went for like
pro vaccine right and you built up this
full list of pro vaccine and then you go
shop that list around it to
antibacterials and be like hey do you
agree with this
no great why not or like here's a login
go to you know
go use it and say where it's wrong and
challenge the stuff that needs to be
challenged
yeah yeah no absolutely those are
valuable tools all right we are at the
10 o'clock mark
should we say goodbye to facebook and
youtube and we will see you next week
this round table everyone's invited we
do it every morning we talk
about every morning every saturday we
talk about our projects
so if you have a project even if your
project is yourself you can come and
tell us and we will do what we did today
but for your project instead of for your
personal life
bring your personal life we'll see let's
just incorporate it into my product
later
and we will see you on friday for our
next board meeting
bye